# Ashraf Ali

### **Software Engineer**

03128915303 | ashraf.ku123@gmail.com | Lyari, Karachi | http://ali-ework.github.io |

Skype: ashraf.ubit



### Summary

Dedicated professional, hardworking individual and highly self-motivated nearly 2 years of experience in mobile application development using native platform (Android & iOS) and cross platform (Ionic & React Native), and Full Stack development using .Net(C#). Known good for teamwork and problem solving.

# **Software Projects Highlight**

#### Kennu Wallet

- > It's your wallet in your smartphone. you can make a purchase at your favorite retail outlet, shop online, request and share money with friends, pay utility bills from home and more. No need to worry about carrying cash or your wallet anymore.
- > Develop with a team of four developers over a five-months' time frame.
- Responsible for developing mobile side of application using Ionic3/Typescript. And server side development using .Net (C#).

#### **Askari Mobile Banking**

- User-friendly mobile app allows you to access your Askari bank account(s) anytime, anywhere.
- > Added new transaction of Cardless cash withdrawals, and international voucher payment service.
- Extending insurance payment transaction.

#### **Bill Payment System**

- It's .Net based web service that communicate with third party provider of utility bill payment, mobile bill payment/top-up, international voucher purchase.
- Integrate Nadra, Onelink and Bank Al Habib for bill payment.
- Integrate Nadra Telco's for mobile top-up.
- Integrate Monami Vouchers for international voucher purchase

#### MeatMart Shop

- Retails Payment based on cash on delivery to track inventory, sales and reports.
- Individually develop admin panel for backend management and client side for placing orders and printing bill receipt, both side development is done using Android native platform and Firebase as real-time database.

# **Experience**

### Wemsol Pvt.Ltd, Karachi May2016-Present

Software Engineer

- Responsible for developing frontend and backend of mobile application.
- Add new features to existing mobile application as client requirement.
- > Integrating third party web services into the existing system.
- Developing web services from scratch using .Net framework C#
- Work closely with senior engineer, designer and producer.
- Work effectively both independently and part of team with minimal supervision.

#### Wemsol Pvt.Ltd, Karachi

Feb2016-Apr2016

Android & iOS Intern

- > Designed, developed, and tested Android and iOS applications
- > Responsible for rapid prototyping and development of mobile applications

### **Additional Experience**

UpWork Jun2017-Sep2017

Freelance Developer

- Work on Chatting application developed using Ionic3 and Firebase, added Geofencing feature to find groups for chatting in particular range.
- > Do reverse engineering work on android applications to find out is either application is storing persistence identifier, location tracking silently, and getting sensitive user profile information

### **Education**

University of Karachi, Karachi, Bachelor of Software Engineer Grade 'B', CGPA '3.07'	2012-2015
Saint Patrick's College, Karachi, HSC (Pre-Engineer) Grade 'A', Percentage '70'	2009-2010
Bright Public School, Karachi, SSC (Science) Grade 'A', Percentage '79'	Till 2008

# **Skills & Abilities**

- Programming Languages: C#, Java, C, C++, Objective C (Basic), Swift(Basic), Assembly.
- Web: Asp.net(C#), Html5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap, jQuery Mobile.
- Operating Systems: Microsoft (Windows), Apple (MAC OS).
- **Database**: SQLServer, Firebase
- **Tools**: VS Code, Android Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio, XCode, Photoshop, MS Office, Matlab, TurboC++.
- Others: Phonegap Cordova, Ionic3, React Native, Typescript, Socket Programming, UML, OOP, Xpath Queries.

# Certification

> Certified in iOS mobile application development (Sylani Welfare).

# Strength

- Great time management skills.
- A high tolerance of stress and enjoy responsibility.
- Quick learner with grasping ability